A Guide to the Samuel Herrick Papers, 1930-1974
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Samuel Herrick Papers, 1930-1974
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1978-002
60.0 cu. ft. 67 boxes, 1 oversize folder
The papers consist of approximately 60 cubic feet of manuscript and printed materials.
Herrick, Samuel, 1911-1974
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Samuel Herrick Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1978.
Biographical Note
Samuel Herrick, generally recognized as the found of the field of astrodymanics, was born in Madison County, Virginia, in 1911. He received a B. S. in Mathematics from Williams College in 1932 and a Ph.D. in Astronomy from the University of California at Berkeley in 1936. Most of his teaching career was spent at the University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA). Herrick served as an instructor in the Astronomy Department from 1937 to 1942; as an assistant professor from 1942 to 1947; as an associate professor from 1947 to 1952; and as a professor from 1952 to 1962. He was the Hunsaker Professor of Astronomy at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology during 1961-1962 and was made a professor in the Astronomy and Engineering Departments at UCLA in 1962. Herrick died in 1974.
Herrick's work applied the classic disciplines of celestial mechanics and mathematics to the special problems of space trajectory research. His studies of the celestial mechanics aspects of space navigation date from 1931, when he received advice and encouragement from R. H. Goddard. As early as 1936, he formulated a development program for the utilization of celestial mechanics in the solution of space navigation problems destined to become real problems only two decades later. In 1946, Herrick instituted a course in Rocket Navigation, the world's first university course designed specifically for astronautics. In 1957, he founded the Astrodynamics Colloquium at UCLA to facilitate communication among scientists engaged in rocket research.
Herrick's publications number over two hundred items, culminating in his comprehensive two-volume work on Astrodynamics, published by Van Nostrand in 1971-1972. His principal contributions to scientific theory are in the areas of orbit determination and ephemeris integration; universal variables; perturbation theory and variation of parameters; differential correction and least squares; space navigation; and sea and air navigation. Further information on Herrick and his accomplishments can be found in the biographical files in Box 1 of the collection.
Scope and Content
The papers consist of approximately 60 cubic feet of manuscript and printed materials. It includes correspondence, notes, drafts of publications, files relating to students and courses, and reprints of the works of others in astronomy and space sciences. Other highlights include Herrick's consulting files for NASA's Project Mercury, the film ""The Day the Earth Stood Still" (1951), and private industry.
Arrangement
The collection is currently unprocessed. A box-level inventory is available in the "Contents List" below, but please note that descriptions of boxes are general and non-inclusive. A printed list of numbered publications from Boxes 27-33 is available in Box 1, as well as the electronic version below.
Please note: Box 66 is not inventoried.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Astrodymanics; Astronomy
Local Subjects:
Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Science and Technology
Contents List
- Biographical Information. (Box 1)
  Scope and Content
  Biographical sketches of SH; biographical directory files; complete and partial bibliographies.
- Course work, correspondence, and subject files, 1931-1968. (Box 2)
  Williams College course notes; SH thesis; first Gaussian and LaPlacian papers (c.1933); correspondence with Robert H. Goddard (1931-1933); consulting files for "The Day the Earth Stood Still" (1951): Williams College correspondence re: honorary degree; Los Angeles Aerospace Advisory Committee (1964-1968); participation in "Los Angeles in Paris" trip (1967-1968).
- Academic and subject files, 1930-1970. (Box 3)
  Academic affairs files (1930-1970); UCLA Astronomy Dept.; Gugeghaim fellowship (1945-1951); UCLA Library History of Science Collection (1944-1952); UCLA astrodymanics field; Hunsaker professorship at MIT (1961-1962).
- SH students' dissertations. (Box 4)
  Junkins; Keesey (prospectus); Smith; Dallas; Newman; Ondrasik; Moyer; Anderson; Kopke; Wong; Hanavan; Jacoby; Lochry.
- SH students' dissertations and academic and publication files. (Box 5 & 8)
  Dissertations: Murphy; Glassman; Kyser; Stroop; copmrehensive exams; MS in astrodynamics candidates.
  "BIPS" series of files (academic activities, reviews of others' works, compliments and criticisms), chiefly 1954-1959.
- Course notes. (Box 6)
  Course notes; outline for space navigation course (1955); astrodynamics courses.
- Subject files. (Box 7)
  Aeronutronics Systems Division (ASD)--Ford series of files, including Project Mercury; Space Trajectory symposium, chiefly 1959-1960.
- Correspondence, 1930-1973. (Box 9)
  A-L (c.1930-1973); Ageton; Aitken; Alfven; Anderson; Archibald; Argentina correspondence; Arias de Greiff; Arlington National Cemetery; Army draft; Army map servie; Berkely Dept; Bisplinghoff; Blanco; Bower; Brouwer; Brower; Bran; Buchanan; California Institute of Technology; Cesco; Chapin; Chebotarev; Chichester; Clemence; Chernykh; Churms; Cole; Comrie; Crawford; Danby; Deprit; Dommanget; Drapers; Duboshin; Duncombe; Durant; Encyclopedia Americana; Feast; French; Fritsch; Gehrels; Harvard University; Herget; Herget, et al re: satellite ephemerides; Hilton; Hirst; IAU circulars; Itzigsohn and Iaunini; Institute of Theoretical Astronomy, USSR; Jet Propulsion Lab; Junkins; King-Hele; Klare; Kepczynski; Koelle; Kopal; Kovalesky; Kuroda; Lanzano; La Paz; Lowden; Libby; Link Foundation; Lochry; Louvens; Lovell; Lyon.
- Correspondence and consulting, 1930-1973. (Box 10 & 11)
  Correspondence M-Z (c. 1930-1973); Makover; Marchal; Marsden; Martin Company; Mayall; McMullen; McVittie; Meeus; Melbourne; Milet; Milwaukee Astronomical Society; Mintz; Moe; Murchie; Musen; Naef; Naval Weapons Lab; Neill; Nicholson; Nishikawa; Oesterwinter; O'Keefe; Paige; Palomar Observatory; Pergammon Press; Perkins; Pilcher; Porter, Cole; Porter, J.G.; Radke; Rasmusen; Reaves; Richey; Roemer; Ross; Roy; Rubenstein; Sadler; Sandorff; Schwartzschild Observatory; Selby; Sellery; Shapiro; Shields; Siry; Sky and Telescope; Soulie; Storms; Stumpff; Summerfield; Szebehely; Takenouchi; Television; Thomas; Todd; Torres; Van Biesbroeck; Vasilevskis; Vincente; Vlasceanu Weems; Wild; Wrigley; Zadunaisky.
  Contracts and consultations, including Army Air Force (1940-1944); NSF Grant G-976 (1954-1960); Western Data Processing Center (1954-1958).
- Consulting. (Box 12)
  Contracts and consultations, including Ohio State Mapping Lab (1959); Lockheed (1962-1963); North American Aviation (1964-1966).
- Presentation and professional societies. (Box 13)
  Presentation and lectures (1955-1964); Professional societies, including American Academy of Mechanics, American Academy of Sciences, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics; American Rocket Society.
- Professional societies. (Box 14)
  Including American Rocket Society, British Interplanetary Society; History of Science Society; International Academy of Astronautics.
- Professional societies and article reprints. (Box 15 & 21)
  Professional societies, including Institute of Navigation and Pacific Rocket Society.
  Reprints S-Z: Sadler; Sandorff; Schneider; Shubart; Sehnal; Shapiro; Sjorgren; Sochilina; Spencer-Jones; Spivak; Sterne; Stumpff; Sundman; Sugai; Taylor; Vaisola; van Flandern; Veis; Vinti; von Zeipel; Votila; Watson; Wetherill; Whipple; Whittaker; Wilkins; Williams; Wolaver; Wong; Yaplee; Yeomans; Zinner.
- "S" series of files, chiefly reprints of articles: S2-S120. (Box 16)
- "S" series of files, chiefly reprints of articles: S121-S263. (Box 17)
- Article reprints. (Box 18)
  Reprints A-D: Aksnes; Alfven; Anderle; Anderson; Arend; Arnold; Baker; Birge; Brouwer; Brown; Burdet; Caputo; Chapin; Charlier; Chebotarev; Clemence; Cohen; Cole; Columbo; Comrie; Crawford; Daney; De Prit.
- Article reprints. (Box 19)
  Reprints D-K: de Sitter; Dubochier; Duncombe; Echert; Ehrlich; Eichorn; Eisenhart; Escobal; Fischer; Francis; French; Fricke; Garfinkel; Gehrels; Giacaglia; Gibbs; Gilvarry; Godal; Goodyear; Guggenheim; Hamid; Herget; Hilton; HIrst; Hunt; Izsak; Jacchia; Jeffreys; Kaula; Kevorkian; King-Hele; Kirkwood; Kisselli.
- Article reprints. (Box 20)
  Reprints K-R: Kopal; Kovalvesky; Kozai; Krause; Krogh; Kustaanheim; Kyner; Lambech; Lancaster; La Paz; La Place; Likins; Liu; Long; Lundquist; Makemson; Marand; Markowitz; Meeus; Melchior; Merson; Message; Mikhailov; Milankovitch; Milham; Milne; Moulton; Mulholland; Musen; Nicholson; O'Keefe; Olmstead; Pierce; Pitken; Prince; Rabe; Rademacher; Rasmusen; Reigber.
- SH Publications. (Box 22)
  Manuscript drafts and notes for Astrodynamics, including chapters 2-3, 6-11, 14, 16-17.
- SH Publications. (Box 23)
  Manuscript drafts for Astrodynamics, appendicies I-IV.
- SH Publications. (Box 24)
  Astrodynamics, miscellaneous drafts, proofs, and revisions.
- SH Publications. (Box 25)
  Astrodynamics errata, V1-ER1, V1-ER2, V1-ER3, V2-ER1; meetings at Republic Aviation re: book chapters; Astrodynamical Reports 1-9, 13-15, 17.
- SH Publications. (Box 26)
  Astrodynamical Reports 2, 5, 7, 15-17; Appendix A to Astrodynamical Report A.
- SH numbered publications (see also listing in Box 1); numbered publications 1-26 (drafts, correspondence, reprints), 1932-1943. (Box 27)
  Publications
  1
  Preliminary orbit of Comet 1932n (Dodwell-Forbes). (with Natalie Ross.) Harvard Announcement Card 252, December 1932.
  2
  Tables for the reduction of radial velocities to the Sun. Lick Observatory Bulletin 470, v. 17, pp. 85-90, May 1935.
  3
  Observations of Comet 1936a (Peltier). (With P. S. Riggs and P. Herget.) Lick Observatory Bulletin 482, v. 17, pp. 196, June 1936.
  4
  Observations of Comet 1936b (Kaho). (With Dorothy Davis.) Harvard Announcement Card 383, July 1936.
  5
  Comet Peltier (1936a). Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 48, pp. 222-224, August 1936
  6
  Preliminary orbit of Comet 1936c (Jackson). (With G. E. Kron and Mary J. Hill.) Harvard Announcement Card 391, September 1936.
  7
  Second orbit of Comet 1936c (Jackson). (With G. E. Kron and Mary J. Hill.) Harvard Announcement Card 395, October 1936; International Astronomical Union Circular 627, October 1936.
  8
  Programme of the final examination for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy. Berkeley, U.C. Press, December 1936
  9
  On the Laplacian and Gaussian orbit methods. Thesis filed with U. C. Berkeley, December 1936. (71 pp.) (Cf. item no. 18.)
  10
  On the Laplacian and Gaussian orbit methods (Abstract). Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 49, pp. 17-23, February 1937. (Cf. item no. 18.)
  11
  The New Whipple Comet. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 49, pp. 108, April 1937.
  12
  Positions of Comet 1936s (Kaho-Kozik-Lis). Lick Observatory Bulletin, 488, v. 18, p. 88, July 1937.
  13
  Leuschner's Method. Collection of formulae for machine computation. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, 6 pp., February 1937.
  14
  Natural-value trigonometric tables. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 50, pp. 234-237, August 1938.
  15
  Meteoritical proofs of the Earth's motions. Popular Astronomy, v.46, pp. 580-581, December 1938; Contribution of the Society for Research on Meteorites, v. 2, pp. 63-64.
  16
  A Proposal for the use of "standard equatorial coordinates." Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v, 51, p. 27-35, February 1939; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, no. 1, v. 1, pp. 1-12
  17
  Smoothing (Abstract). Publications of the American Astronomical Society, v. 9, p. 261, November 1939.
  18
  The Laplacian and Gaussian orbit methods. University of California Publications, Contributions of the Los Angeles Astronomical Department, v. 1, pp. 1-56, December 1940. (A revision of item No. 9.)
  19
  The Jupiter-Saturn triple conjunction. American Astronomical Society Leaflet, n. 144, February 1941. (8 pp.)
  20
  The "Phantom Bertha" mystery. Popular Astronomy, v. 49, pp. 102-104, February 1941; Contributions of the Society for Research on Meteorites, v. 2, pp. 247-249.
  21
  The determination of position from a photographic plate. University of California Publications, Contributions of the Los Angeles Astronomical Department, v. 1, pp. 57-72, December 1941.
  22
  Position line graphs. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, December 28, 1942. (4 pp.) (Cf. item no. 27.)
  23
  Position line graph no. 3, for use with navigation chart no. 3, latitudes 25 to 35 degrees, altitudes 30 to 60 degrees. Berkeley, U.C. Press, December 28, 1942. (1 sheet, 21x56 inches.) (Cf. item no. 27.)
  24
  Navigation chart no. 3, for celestial navigation, dead reckoning, etc., and especially for use as a part of Position Line Graphs.
  25
  Review of C. C. Wylie, Astronomy, Maps, and Weather (New York, Harpers, 1942) and other books. Popular Astronomy, v. 51, pp. 56-58, January 1943.
  26
  The emergency determination of a fix and the index correction of a bubble sextant. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, February 1943. (3 pp.)
- SH numbered publications (see also listing in Box 1); numbered publications 27-61 (drafts, correspondence, reprints), 1943-1950. (Box 28)
  27
  Position line graphs. Berkeley, U.C. Press, March 1943; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, No. 2, v. 1, pp. 13-20.
  28
  Navigational precomputation without an altitude graph. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, June 4, 1943. (5 pp.) (Cf. item No. 64.)
  29
  Grid Navigation: I. How to navigate a straight line on a non-Mercator chart. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, September 3, 1943. (9 pp.) (Cf. item No. 36.)
  30
  Grid Navigation II. Radio fixes: plotting a bearing from a station off the chart. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, September 3, 1943. (2 pp.) (Cf. item No. 36.)
  31
  Grid Navigation III. A comparison of projections for navigation. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, September 3, 1943. (4 pp.) (Cf. item No. 36.)
  32
  The accuracy of Ageton's method. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, January 12, 1944. (3pp.) (Cf. item No. 39.)
  33
  The Air Almanac refraction tables. Photolithographed and mimeographed, Los Angeles, January 19, 1944. (1 p. plus 1 sheet.) (Cf. item No. 42.)
  34
  Astronomy 12: Introduction. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, March 22, 1944. (9pp.) (For student use only.)
  35
  Provisional sunrise and sunset refraction tables. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, July 11, 1944. (2 pp.)
  36
  Grid navigation. Geographical Review, 34, 436-456, July 1944; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, No. 3, v. 1, pp. 21-46. (A revision of item Nos. 29, 30, 31.)
  37
  Grid Variation, 1945. California-Hawaii area. (GV1) Lithographed, Los Angeles, July 14, 1944. (1 sheet.) 1 in.=2 degrees.
  38
  Grid variation, 1945. United States. (GV2) Lithographed, Los Angeles, July 14, 1944. (1 sheet.) 1:5,000,000.
  39
  "The accuracy of Ageton's method in celestial navigation." Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 56, pp. 149-155, August 1944; "The accuracy of Ageton's method in celestial navigation." Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v/ 56, pp. 149-155, August 1944; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, No. 4, v. 1, pp. 47-54. (A revision of item No. 32; cf. also No. 46.)
  40
  Grid Variation, 1945. North Atlantic. (GV3) Lithographed, Los Angeles, Sept. 21, 1944. (1 sheet.) 1:500,000,000.
  41
  Grid variation, 1945, Alaska. (GV4) Lithographed, Los Angeles, September 27, 1944. (1 sheet.) 1:500,000,000.
  42
  The Air Almanac refraction tables. United States Naval Institute Proceedings, v. 70, pp. 1140-1141, September 1944; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, No. 5, v. 1, pp. 55-58. (Cf. item No. 33.)
  43
  Ephemeris of Jupiter's ninth satellite. (With June Daus.) Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v.56, p. 203, October 1944.
  44
  "Nearly parabolic" and "nearly rectilinear" orbits. (Abstract) Astronomical Journal, v. 51, p. 123, June 1945. (Cf Nos. 57, 80.)
  45
  Rounding-off notation. Math Tables and Other Aids to Computation, v. 1, p. 432, July 1945.
  46
  The accuracy of Ageton. Log of Navigation, v. 3, No. 9, p. 26, September 1945. A condensation of No. 30 by the editors of Log.
  47
  1946 ephemeris of Jupiter's ninth satellite. (With June Daus.) Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 57, p. 267, October 1945.
  48
  Instrumental solutions in celestial navigation. Navigation, v. 1, pp. 22-27, June 1946.
  49
  Revising the Nautical Almanac. Navigation, v. 1, pp. 59-60. September 1946.
  50
  As tabuas de refracao do Alamaque Americano do Ar. Revista Maritima Brasileira, v. 66, pp. 75-76, with one insert, September 1946. No. 42 translated into the Portuguese by Capitao de Fragata Renato Bayardino.
  51
  Ephemeris of Jupiter's ninth satellite. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 59, p. 34, February 1947.
  52
  Review of W. Myerscough and W. Hamilton, Rapid Navigation Tables. Math Tables and Other Aids to Computation, v. 2, pp. 275-276, April 1947.
  53
  Ephemeris of Jupiter's ninth satellite. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 60, p. 116, April 1948.
  54
  Rocket Navigation (A first draft of portions of text.) Mimeographed. Los Angeles, July 1948. (34 pp.)
  55
  A modification of the "variation of constants" method for special perturbations. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 60, pp. 321-323, October 1948; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, v. 1, No. 6, pp. 59-62.
  56
  1949 ephemeris of Jupiter's ninth satellite. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 61, p. 136, June 1949.
  57
  Tables for nearly parabolic and rectilinear orbits. Astronomical Journal, v. 54, p. 189, September 1949, (Cf. Nos. 44, 80.)
  58
  Some chapters from Rocket Navigation. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, December 1949. (137 pp.) Chapters 2, 5, 6, 8, 9, 11.
  59
  1950 ephemeris of Jupiter's ninth satellite. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 62, p. 55, April 1950.
  60
  The measurement and reduction of photographic positions. Outline lecture notes. Mimeographed. Los Angeles, July 1950. (36 pp.)
  61
  Space rocket trajectories. Journal of the British Interplanetary Society, v. 9, pp. 235-241, September 1950.; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, No. 10, v. 1, pp. 97-103.
- SH numbered publications (see also listing in Box 1); numbered publications 62-110 (drafts, correspondence, reprints), 1950-1957. (Box 29)
  62
  Interplanetary navigation. Special publication of the Radio Technical Commission for Aeronautics, 4 pp. October 27, 1950; Navigation, supplement to v. 2, December 1950. (Cf. No. 70.)
  63
  Rocket Navigation. Navigation, v. 2 pp. 259-272, December 1950; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers No. 11, v. 1, pp. 107-122.
  64
  A short method for precomputation. Navigation, v. 2, pp. 321-324, March 19512. (Cf. No. 28.)
  65
  1951 ephemeris of Jupiter's ninth satellite. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 63, pp. 88-89, April 1951.
  66
  Ephemeris of 1566 Icarus. Minor Planet Circulars 555-556, April 20, 1951.
  67
  Step-by-step integration of x=f(x, y, z, t) without a "corrector." Math Tables and Other Aids to Computation, v. 5, pp. 61-67, April 1951; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers No. 12, v. 1, pp. 123-130.
  68
  A differential correction for the methods of Lagrange and Gauss-Gibbs. Astronomical Journal, v. 56, pp. 128-129, October 1951.
  69
  Jupiter XII. Harvard Announcement Card 1156, November 14, 1951; International Astronomical Union Circular 1334, November 23, 1951; Sky and Telescope, v. 11, p. 80, February 1952. (First three-body orbit solution on a Gibbsian pattern.)
  70
  Interplanetary navigation. Navigation, v. 3, pp. 57-59, September-December 1951. (Cf. No. 62.)
  71
  More chapters from rocket navigation. Mimeographed, Los Angeles, December 1951. Chapters 10, 12, 13, 15, in part.
  72
  Review of Willy Ley's Rockets, Missiles, and Space Travel. Sky and Telescope, v. 11, pp. 92-93, February 1952.
  73
  The mean longitude or mean anomaly in perturbations by variation of constants. Astronomical Journal, v. 56, pp. 186-188, February 1952; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, v. 1, pp. 1-4.
  74
  Orbit and ephemeris of minor planet 1950 CJ. (With J.L. Brady, Jr. and C. G. Hilton.) Minor Planet Circulars 731, March 1952.
  75
  Elements and ephemeris of 1950 BW. (With C. G. Hilton and J. L. Brady, Jr.) Minor Planet Circulars 743-644, March 1952.
  76
  Ephemeris of 1566 Icarus. (With C. G. Hilton and J. L. Brady, Jr.) Minor Planet Circulars 773, May 1952.
  77
  Tycho Brahe. Navigation, v. 3, pp. 108-109, June 1952. Original version in U.C.L.A. Library Acquisitive Notes, No. 11, March 1952.
  78
  Jupiter IX and Jupiter XII. Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 64, pp. 237-241, October 1952; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, v. 1, pp. 131-138.
  79
  The minor planet Icarus. Observatory, v. 73, pp. 15-17, February 1953.
  80
  Tables for rocket and comet orbits. National Bureau of Standards, Applied Mathematics Series No. 20, March 9, 1953. xxiv + 100 pp. (Cf. Nos. 44, 57.)
  81
  Observation residuals for Icarus. Minor Planet Circulars 937, June 24, 1953. (Cf. No. S38.)
  82
  Ephemeris of (1566) Icarus. Minor Planet Circulars 946, June 30, 1953; International Astronomical Union Circulars 1413, July 15, 1953; Harvard Announcement Card 1216, July 27, 1953.
  83
  Icarus and variation of parameters. Astronomical Journal, 58, 156-164, August 1953; U.C.L.A. Astronomical Papers, v. 2, no. 2, pp. 6-14.
  84
  Space Navigation. California Monthly, September 1953.
  85
  Ephemeris of Jupiter's Ninth Satellite. (With Charles G. Hilton.) Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 65, pp. 294-295, December 1953.
  86
  Jupiter XII. (With Charles G. Hilton.) Harvard Announcement Card 1238, January 13, 1954.
  87
  Observation residuals of Icarus. Minor Planet Circulars 1401, February 1954. (Cf. No. S44.)
  88
  1954 ephemeris of (1566) Icarus. (With Charles G. Hilton.) Harvard Announcement Card 1247, May 25, 1954; International Astronomical Union Circulars 1452, May 1954; Minor Planet Circulars 1099, July 15, 1954.
  89
  1954 ephemeris of (1580) Betulia. (With Charles G. Hilton.) Minor Planet Circulars 1130, October 20, 1954.
  90
  Improved elements and 1954-55 ephemeris for Object Wilson-Minkowski 1951 RA. (With Charles G. Hilton.) Minor Planet Circulars 1131, October 20, 1954.
  91
  Improved elements and 1954-55 ephemeris of Object Wirtanen 1948 EA. (With Charles G. Hilton and Gerald L. Matlin.) Minor Planet Circulars 1132, October 20, 1954.
  92
  Elements of (1566) Icarus. Ephemerides of Minor Planets, 1955, p. 40. (Leningrad, 1954.)
  93
  1955 Ephemeris of (1566) Icarus. Minor Planets for 195 5. pp. 1, 7. (Cincinnati Observatory, 1954.)
  94
  Armin Otto Leuschener. Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, v. 114, pp. 295-298, December 1954.
  95
  1954-55 ephemerides of Jupiter's ninth and twelfth satellites. (With C. G. Hilton and Gerald L. Matlin.) Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, v. 66, pp. 336-337, December 1954.
  96
  Observation residuals of Icarus. Minor Planet Circulars 1220, May 11, 1955.
  97
  1955 ephemeris of (1566) Icarus. (With C. G. Hilton.) Minor Planet Circulars 1243, June 8, 1955.
  98